MANALI DARJI

Toronto, ON | +1 (437) 981-3559 | darjimanali93@gmail.com | Portfolio: manalidarji.github.io

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Senior UI Developer with 6+ years experience and specialization in HTML, CSS & Javascript development. Designed websites and applications that increased user engagement by 25% and resolved persistent browser compatibility issues for Firefox & Internet Explorer users whilst rigorously adhering to project deadlines.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Technologies and Tools: HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, ES6, Jquery, ReactJs, HandlebarJs, NodeJs, ExpressJs, PHP, WordPress, Java, Java Spring Boot, REST API, MySQL, MongoDB, Photoshop, Figma, GitHub, Trello
- Professional Skills: Website Optimization, Agile, and Scrum methodologies, Modular Programming, SEO, Design Patterns and Principles, Effective Communication.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer | Giatec Smart Construction Solutions

May 2022 - Present

- Created website layout/user interfaces using HTML, CSS, JQuery by using standard web development practices in order to deliver quality user experience.
- Worked on rebranding of the company's main website as per latest design standards, resulting in increase of organic traffic and improvement in revenue by 15%.
- Analyzed and fixed the errors, warnings and notices on the websites, provided by Semrush Tool thus increasing the site
 health by 8%.
- Analyzed and fixed Google Tag Manager(GTM) issues thus re-gaining analytics data on the dashboard.

Senior User Interface(UI) Developer | Media.net Software Services Pvt. Ltd

Jul 2017 - Aug 2021

- Implemented Single Page Applications(SPAs) using ReactJs, React-Router as Front-End Technology by consuming REST API.
- Implemented custom WordPress themes from scratch as per the designs for 15+ websites.
- Implemented headless WordPress websites consuming WP REST API using ReactJs to build its front-end, thus eliminating the need of WordPress themes.
- Analyzed, designed and implemented REST API using NodeJs, ExpressJs and Java Spring Boot.
- Collaborated with Business, Design, Back-End and QA Teams to deliver highly optimized websites.
- Implemented Google Analytics and Facebook Pixel Code which helped the business team understand various user's interaction with the website, thus increasing the overall revenue by 15%.
- Mentored 3 new employees to achieve high performance of the team and meet all business goals.

Software Engineer | Capgemini

Jun 2014 - Jun 2017

- Experienced with Software Development Life Cycle(SDLC) following Agile Methodology.
- Created automated test cases for Functional and Regression testing based on the requirements using Ranorex Studio to decrease testing time by 60%.
- Reviewed and reported software bug reports, highlighting problem areas.
- Experienced in executing SQL queries in order to view successful transactions and validation of data.

EDUCATION

- Advanced Diploma Database Application Developer | Seneca College | Aug 2022
- Bachelor of Engineering | University of Mumbai | May 2014